Diego Escobedo

Boston, MA | diegoesc@mit.edu | 650-445-9879

Rising Leader in Computer Science and Economics

Trilingual MIT Junior with a unique blend of computer science proficiency and understanding of the economic contexts in which data science can be a driving force. Sound foundation in machine learning, market design, and algorithms research.

Education

Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT)

Class of 2022

- Candidate for B.S. in Computer Science & Engineering and B.S. in Mathematical Economics GPA 4.6/5
- Relevant Coursework: Introduction to ML, Design and Analysis of Algorithms, Fundamentals of Programming, Optimization Methods: Business Analytics, Math for Computer Science, Probabilistic Systems Analysis, Linear Algebra
- Academic Interests: Combinatorial Optimization, Resource Allocation Problems, Algorithms, Big Data, Public Policy

Work Experience

Google - STEP Intern

Summer 2020

Mountain View, CA

• Designed a fantasy basketball engine where users could build a custom team, insert them into a real NBA season, and use a neural network to predict the outcome of a match between any two teams.

Electronic Arts (EA) - Global Analytics and Insights Intern

Summer 2019

Maxis Studios

Google Research

Redwood City, CA

- Designed a ML model to optimize targeted advertising and improve business KPIs, leveraging data from ~2M players.
- Created daily reports and produced ad-hoc analysis for a variety of business units and studio leadership, as well as a long-term project building out Maxis' data infrastructure.

MIT Media Lab - Undergraduate Researcher

Winter 2018

Viral Communications Group – Layer Project

Cambridge, MA

• Developed a naïve Bayes recommendation model with a multivariate Bernoulli event model that maintained privacy by performing binary representation matrix calculations on end devices.

Stanford School of Medicine - Molecular Imaging Program Intern

Multi-Modality Imaging Lab

Summer 2017 – Spring 2018 Stanford, CA

• Invented a 'smart toilet' that analyzes bodily fluids to enable the early detection of diseases such as diabetes, UTIs, and STIs, by analyzing biometric data to create a longitudinal profile of patients' health. Patent pending, filed July 2018.

Leadership Experience

MIT Inter-Fraternity Council (IFC)

December 2019 - Present

Vice-President

• Established and led the Diversity Committee and Constitution Review Committee, in order to celebrate the diversity of one of MIT's largest student organizations and make our governing documents reflect that.

Phi Delta Theta - Massachusetts Gamma Chapter

September 2018 – Present

President

May 2020 – Present

Misc: Recruitment, Judicial, Social, Academics Chair

December 2018 – May 2020

• As President, redesigned the bylaws, improved our safety procedures, and funded a house renovation. Responsible for coordinating over 20 officers' efforts in a variety of areas, including recruitment, social, and academic endeavors.

Other

- Programming Languages/Tools: Python, SQL, Tensorflow, Git, Java, JavaScript, HTML, Julia, Google App Engine
- Languages: Fully trilingual in Spanish, English, and Portuguese
- **Publications:** A mountable toilet system for personalized health monitoring via the analysis of excreta. Nat Biomed Eng (2020). https://doi.org/10.1038/s41551-020-0534-9